Goooooo!
上啊啊啊！
Shit!
見鬼
What is this?
怎麼回事？
It's here. It's here!
它來了 它來了！
It's finally here!
它終於來了！
本字幕由 SweetSub 製作　僅做交流學習之用途
翻校：ピロピラ ピロコ　其它：tastySugar
Are you satisfied now?
你現在滿意了？
All this. This is what you wanted, right?
這一切 這就是你想要的 對嗎？
Your dream's being fulfilled,
你的夢想實現了
so just go back and leave us alone!
那就回去 不要再來糾纏我們！
And give Ide back, please.
還有 求求你 把井出還給我
Hibaji, were you listening to anything I taught in class?
雲雀弄 你在學校上課都不聽講的嗎？
"Give this back! Give that back!
「把這個還給我！把那個還給我！
Oh, give it back, please,
求求你 還給我
because it's all about what I want.
因為這一切只與我想要什麼有關
I want everything to be mine! Give it to me! More!"
我什麼都想要 給我！更多！」
You're like a child throwing a tantrum.
你就像個耍脾氣的小鬼
You think you get things by asking,
你覺得開口索求就能如願
that if you're stomping, crying on the floor,
跺著腳 在地上哭
people will just drop things in your lap?
別人就會把東西放在你面前？
Then what am I supposed to do?
那我該怎麼做？
Hand it over.
交出來
If you want something you don't have, then you must hand over what you do have.
想要什麼東西 就要拿你擁有的東西來換
That's called balance.
這就叫平衡
You're making a deal?
你想做交易？
That isn't really appropriate for a teacher.
作為老師這不合適吧
This is the last thing I'll teach you.
這是我教你的最後一件事
You just have to give your power to me.
你只要把力量給我就可以了
Is that your final answer?
這就是你的最終答案嗎？
You're responsible for your own responses.
怎麼回應是你的自由
Despite what you may think, I have learned.
也許與你所想不同 但我確實明白了
It's time to stop acting childish,
是時候停止幼稚的行為了
and that's why I'm just gonna take it.
因此我要親手奪回來
You get a gold star!
獎勵你一朵小紅花
That's it. Give it to me!
就是這樣 把它給我！
More! More!
更多！更多！
Hurry. We need to evacuate.
快點！我們要撤離了
Come on! I'm right here!
來啊！正面上我啊！
Thank you, Hibaji.
謝啦 雲雀弄
The time has finally come.
終於到時候了
Come to me, Atomsk.
到我這裡來 Atomsk
Huh?! Wait! Wait! Wait!
蛤？等等等等等！
It's huge!
好大！
Oh, this doesn't look so --
看起來不——
Please, help me!
救 救命！
This is bad. We have to get out of here, Captain.
不妙 隊長 我們撤離吧
No! We can't!
不 不行
Gather round, men. Listen to me.
集合  聽我說
You young'uns are the ones who'll fuel space.
你們這些年輕人將是宇宙的燃料
I am never going to give up on you!
我絕不會放棄你們！
Hey, are you okay?
你沒事吧？
The champ's all right with a champ's destructive punch.
受了冠軍的重擊 但是冠軍沒事
Aiko. You actually came back for me.
愛子 你居然回來找我了
Unfortunately, it's a bit too late now.
可惜 已經太晚了
Medical Mechanica is somehow planning on capturing that monster with his mochi,
Medical Mechanica 似乎想要用麻薯抓住那個怪物
but I don't think it's possible, and the potted plant is missing.
但是我覺得這是不可能的 還有那個花盆也不見了
Aiko, you were supposed to be our last hope.
愛子 你本應該是我們最後的希望
Who would have guessed that when it came time,
沒想到 到了應該使用你的時候
I wouldn't be able to bring myself to use you?
我卻不忍心下手了
Take this and get out of here.
拿好這個 走吧
I don't want it.
不要
Just take it! I know you've been saving this money.
拿走！我知道你一直在存錢
You were planning to buy your freedom!
你想要贖買自己的自由
You may as well take it. It's prize money.
拿走吧 這是勝者的獎金
There's been a knockout, and the 10 count has already begun.
已經 KO 了 讀秒已經開始了
Aiko, you're finally free. Now go!
愛子 你自由了 走吧！
What should I do?
我該怎麼辦？
That potted plant... the trigger
那個花盆… 觸發裝置…
Oh, God. That was just the worst.
天啊 真是糟透了
Where the hell did my bat go? Huh?
我的球棒呢？
What's wrong? You were doing so well just a little while ago.
怎麼了？剛剛不還好好的
Canti!
Canti
Is this a real date?
這算真正的約會嗎？
I'll call it a date if you shut up!
你閉嘴的話就算
You want the pot, right? It's probably at Ide's place.
你要花盆的話 應該是在井出家裡
Perhaps it was something you ate that didn't suit you.
也許你吃了不該吃的東西
Oh, dear.
天啊
-Oh, Mori. -Oh, hi, Hibajiri's mom.
-啊 森君 -你好 雲雀弄夫人
Goodness. Is this your girlfriend?
啊啦 這是女朋友嗎？
-Why, yes, ma'am. -No, I'm not.
-當然啦！-才不是
Okay, Ide! Since you're not home, I'm coming in!
井出 既然你不在家 我就進來了！
Hey, by the way, what do you want from Ide?
對了 您過來是為什麼？
Well, Hidomi hasn't come home yet.
酷美還沒有回家
I was hoping she'd be here, maybe.
我想她會不會在這裡
Why would you think she'd be here?
為什麼您覺得她會在這裡
I was thinking they were dating, maybe.
我以為他們在交往
Why does Ide get all the ladies?
為什麼井出的桃花運這麼好
That was fast.
這麼快
-Oh, my. Is something wrong? -Aiko
-哎呀 怎麼了？-愛子？
Oh, God, Aiko!
天啊！愛子！
Oh, dear, what's going on?
你怎麼了？
-Are you okay?  Say something! -Mommy？
-你沒事吧？說話呀！-媽媽？
No way.
怎麼會
Hidomi? Hidomi, is that you?
酷美？ 酷美 是你嗎？
Oh, sweetie, you're not hurt, are you?
親愛的 你沒事吧？
Mommy has been worried to death about you.
媽媽我好擔心
Have you?
騙人
Have you? You don't really care.
你才不在乎呢
You've stopped caring about me.
你已經不在乎我了
You're quitting, closing the cafe.
你放棄了 你關掉了咖啡店
It's the same with Dad.
你和父親一樣
You don't care about him, either.
你也不在乎他
When your father took off for the plant,
在你父親去工廠之前
he left the cafe in my care,
他把咖啡店留給我
just like he left those headphones of yours.
就像他把耳機留給你一樣
Sorry to tell you this, but it's not here.
很抱歉 但是不在這裡
Well, that's a problem.
那可麻煩了
Maybe, maybe not.
或許還有救
Perhaps the reason he came was to get it back.
也許他回來的理由就是想取回它
I was foolish.
我真傻
I thought as long as I was at the cafe with you,
我以為只要我和你在一起經營咖啡店
I would be able to wait for him, no matter how long it took.
我就可以一直等下去 等他回來
All I wanted was for life to stay the same as it was,
我想要的只是生活和以前一樣
so the day that he came back would be the day I could finally become a real mother to you.
當他回來的時候 我就可以成為你真正的母親
Until then, I'll do my best to be a good mommy.
在那之前 我會努力做一個好媽媽
High-strung, but it doesn't look it nya
弦上的很緊 但是看起來不是喵
If it's your bat you seek, it's there.
如果你想要你的球棒 它在那裡
I was wrong, though, unrealistic.
但是我錯了 忘記了現實
You are bound to keep changing, Hidomi.
酷美 你注定是要改變的
You were bound to fall in love, bound to become an adult.
你注定會喜歡上某人 注定要長大成人
That's the reason why.
這就是為什麼
Then let's do it together.
那麼我們一起吧
The cafe.
咖啡店
Let's run it together,
我們一起開吧
not because we're waiting for Dad,
不是為了等父親回來
but because it's where home is and where I want to be,
而是因為那是我們的家 是我想要生活的地方
and the only thing that doesn't change is the fact that I can change myself.
如果說有什麼不會改變 那就是我可以改變自己
Oh, Hidomi.
酷美
Wait for me. Okay, Mom?
等我回來好嗎？媽媽
Please hurry.
早點回來
Come back soon, Hidomi. We have a cafe to run.
早點回家 酷美 咖啡店還等著開門呢
Wait for me.
等我
FLCL Progressive
Ms. Haruko.
晴子老師
Did you calm down? Want some tea?
你冷靜下來了？要喝茶嗎？
This power, I'm gonna use it for myself.
這份力量 我要為自己使用
Hmph. Sounds good.
不錯哦
Who would've guessed the kid would be all selfless and noble?
誰說這小鬼會高尚無私的
I'm getting out of here, and I'm taking Ide back with me, too.
我要從這裡逃出去 而且我要把井出也帶回去
That sounds good, too.
這也挺好嘛
That said, not thinking about what could happen next is what makes you a kid.
不過 就因為你做事不計後果 才只能做一個小鬼
If you take that off, Hibaji, you won't be able to stay human.
把耳機摘下來的話 你就無法維持人類的形態了
Guess you're all alone.
你會是孤獨一人
Do you still want to do it?
你確定要這麼做喵？
Hey, aren't you...
你是…
Canti?
Canti？
Pretty awesome.
挺厲害的嘛
So, shall we make our way out of here, then?
我們從這裡逃出去吧？
I was wondering the same thing.
我也這麼想
A lot of crap got sucked in, after all,
好多垃圾都被吸進來了
so we've just got to make sure to be careful.
所以一定要小心
It's too hard! I can't do it!
太難了 我踩不動了
Is this the place?
是這裡嗎？
What an odd girl she is.
真是個古怪的小姑娘
I prefer unique!
是獨特！
That's what you call unique?
這是你說的獨特？！
Uh, that's right.
沒錯
Out of my way!
別擋路！
There it is. I can make it!
那裡 能成功的
I was supposed to make it!
我應該能出去的!
That's what happens in the movies!
電影裡都是那麼演的!
There's another one.
還有一處
Canti!
The hell? Where'd it go?
什麼鬼？到哪裡去了？
It's Atomsk.
是 Atomsk
Ide!
井出！
-Come on, Atomsk. Come back! -Come on! Come out!
-喂 Atomsk 回來！-出來啊 井出！
I see. I have to take it.
好吧 我要上了
That's right.
沒錯
If you want it, then take it!
想要的話就去拿！
I'll take this!
看招！
Oh, go away, Hibaji! Stop cock-blocking!
走開 雲雀弄！別來掃興！
Damn it!
可惡！
Wait.
等等
What is...
怎麼…
Ide!
井出！
Okay. You better not run away.
好吧 你可不要跑
You became mine.
你成為了我的所有物
Didn't you, Atomsk?
不是嗎 Atomsk？
Why? Why?
為什麼？為什麼？
Why the hell won't you?!
到底為什麼？
It's been so long.
那麼久…
I've been chasing you for so long.
我追逐了你那麼久
Why do you keep refusing to be mine?!
為什麼你不願意成為我的所有物？！
You are mine! I'm telling you!
你是我的！我告訴你！
You're mine! You're mine!
你是我的！你是我的！
You are!
你是！
Why won't you...look at me?
你為什麼…不願意看我？
Can't you see my body is overflowing?
我的身體都溢出了
When you were a kid,
當你還小的時候…
did you ever try drawing a picture of going to see fireworks with your family,
你有沒有試著畫過自己和家人一起去看煙火
only to fail?
但卻畫不出來？
You're back.
你醒了！
You try to draw the countless   specks of light that you saw,
你想要畫出你看見的無數光點
but the only way to recreate the night sky
但是重現夜空的唯一方法
is to color everything in with a black pencil.
就是用黑色鉛筆把一切都塗上顏色
They were lighting up that dark sky,
它們照亮了夜空
and they were so colorful and beautiful.
絢爛奪目
All beautiful things eventually fade away.
所有美麗的事物最終都將消逝
I thought, this time for sure,
我以為這次一定可以的…
that I was gonna get what I was fighting for.
一定可以得到我想要的
So an all-out attack didn't work, huh?
所以火力齊發也沒有奏效啊
You can go home now.
你可以回家了
Wait. What was the reason for doing all this?
所以這一切到底是為了什麼？
No reason for any of it.
沒什麼理由
That thing probably didn't come for a specific reason, either.
那傢伙過來大概也沒什麼特別的理由
Oh, my tummy!
我的肚子好痛！
What are you gonna do now?
你現在打算做什麼？
If at first you don't succeed...
失敗是…
You haven't learned.
你真是不長教訓
'Cause I'm an adult.
因為我是個大人
The fact that you can't catch it is what makes you want to chase it.
追尋只是因為無法抓獲
The fact that you can't reach it is what makes you want to chase it.
追尋只是因為觸碰不到
You are correct.
沒錯
Ms. Haruko.
晴子老師
What?
怎啦？
Well -- Well, you and I know we experienced many different things on many different occasions,
呃 你和我發生了很多事情
and I appreciate your feelings. I do.
我很感激 真的
I'm really sorry, but I can't --
對不起 但是我
While I like you, I confess, I don't feel the same way.
雖然我喜歡你 但是這是不一樣的
Forgive me!
對不起！
Ms. Haruko?
晴子老師？
Oh, man. I'm so wounded by you.
我好受傷
I can't face you. I must run away.
我沒辦法面對你了 我得走了
Do whatever you want 'cause I'll be doing the same.
想做就做吧 因為我也會做同樣的事
Haruko out!
晴子退場！
Long time no see, boys.
好久不見 孩子們
-Chief? -Oh, how cute.
-長官？-真可愛
You have tiny eyebrows just like your father.
你跟你父親一樣 眉毛都那麼小
Oh, no, don't look! It's so embarrassing!
別看！好害羞！
There's nothing I want to be.
我對自己毫無期待
There's nothing I want to do,
我什麼事情都不想做
and that's probably not the best way to be,
這也許不是什麼好事
but you know what? It probably doesn't matter.
但是 這也許沒什麼